A Guide to the Cary Reich papers FA1275
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Oral History Audio, circa 1980s (Bulk: 1982); 2
  - C-D, 2.2
    - Douglass, Robert, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9519)
      Interview. Douglass was first assistant counsel (1964-1965), counsel (1965-1971), and secretary (1971-1972) to Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Dudley, George - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9520)
      Interview. Dudley was an architect and gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller. Dudley worked alongside Wallace Harrison in designing and building the United Nations headquarters, Rockefeller Center, Lincoln Center, and the Empire State Plaza in Albany, New York. He also served with Rockefeller at various times in the Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs; International Basic Economies Corporation; New York State Office of Regional Development; and the Pure Water Authority.
    - Dudley, George - Part 2, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9521A)
    - Dudley, George - Part 3, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette; Sound, 285 minutes (Tape AV 9521B)
    - Dudley, George - Part 4, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette; Sound, 141 minutes (Tape AV 9521C)
    - Duggan, Stephen, 1982 September 22?; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9523)
      Interview. Duggan was a classmate of Nelson Rockefeller at the Lincoln School in Manhattan.
    - Dunham, Richard, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9524)
      Interview. Dunham was deputy budget director and then director of the budget for Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Dunham was also deputy director of the White House Domestic Council when Rockefeller was Vice President. Dunham interview ends at 234 minutes, 28 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Robert MacCrate until end. MacCrate was Counsel to the Governor for Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Duryea Jr., Perry, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9525)
      Interview. Duryea was a Republican member of New York State Assembly; served as Speaker of the Assembly from 1969 to 1973.
  - E-G, 2.3
    - Edelman, Peter, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9526)
      Interview. Edelman was issues director for Arthur Goldberg's New York gubernatorial campaign.
    - Edelstein, Julius, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9527)
      Interview. Edelstein was executive assistant to New York City Mayor Robet F. Wagner. Edelstein interview ends at 46 minutes, 45 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual until end.
    - Egan, John, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9528)
      Interview. Egan was commissioner of the Office of General Services.
    - Emery, James, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9529)
      Interview. Emery was Livingston County Sheriff and then a New York State Assemblyman.
    - Engel, David, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9530)
      Interview. Engel was a landscape architect.
    - Erb, Claude, 1982 October 2; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9531)
      Interview. Erb was a historian.
    - Esposito, Meade, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9532)
      Interview. Esposito served as Brooklyn Democratic Chair.
    - Fishbein, Peter, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9533)
      Interview. Fishbein served in Nelson Rockfeller's 1968 Presidential campaign; campaign manager for Arthur Goldberg's unsuccessful 1970 New York gubernatorial campaign.
    - Feist, Enid, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9534)
      Interview. Feist was Nelson Rockefeller's deputy campaign director for New York City.
    - Feldman, Justin, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9535)
      Interview. Feldman was a Democratic official.
    - Fish, Marianne, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9536)
      Interview. Fish was Myrtie Tinklepaugh's daughter. Tinklepaugh was a Republican county chairman. Fish interview ends at 74 minutes, 5 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with John Camp until end. Camp was an AIA-IBEC aide.
    - Fisher, Arnold, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15679)
      Interview. Fisher was Republican Party chair of Madison County, New York.
    - Fisher, Harold, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9537)
      Interview. Fisher served as chair of the Metropolitan Transit Authority (MTA) during Governor Nelson Rockefeller's tenure. Fisher interview ends at 89 minutes, 17 seconds. Tape then contains parital interview with Ron Maiorana until end. Maiorana was press secretary and advisor to Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Ford, Gerald, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9538)
      Interview. Ford was the 38th President of the United States.
    - Ford: Panel IIA: The Rockefeller Vice-Presidency, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9539)
      Interview. Panelists include Richard Rosenbaum, Joseph Persico, Peter Wallison, Richard Dunham, and James Cannon. Rosenbaum was appointed by Governor Nelson Rockefeller to the New York State Supreme Court. Persico was chief speech writer for Rockefeller when he was governor and vice president. Wallison was special assistant to Governor Rockefeller. Dunham was deputy director and then director of the budget for New York. Cannon was assistant to Governor Rockefeller.
    - Forster, Bayard Stuyvesant, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9540)
      Interview. Forster was New York State commissioner of transportation under Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Forster interview ends at 46 minutes, 45 seconds. Tape then contains a phone call with a Mrs. Smith until 61 minutes, 6 seconds. Tape then contains parital interview with Bill Lovelock until end. Lovelock was a detective lieutenant for the NYPD and a bodyguard for Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Franciscus, John, 1982 May 5; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9541)
      Interview. Franciscus worked for IBEC.
    - Free, Lloyd, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9542)
      Interview. Free was a political pollster who conducted surveys for Nelson Rockefeller's various campaigns. Free interview ends at 56 minutes, 56 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Wilma Rogalin. Rogalin was vice chair of the New York State Republican Committee and president of its Women's Federation.
    - French, Eleanor Clark, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9543)
      Interview. French was a cousin of Mary Clark Rockefeller, wife of John French (NAR's roommate at Dartmouth), and a Democratic activist who was the national president of Americans for Democratic Action. French interview ends at 65 minutes, 44 seconds. Tape then contains parital interview with unidentified individual until end.
    - Friedman, Josh, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9544)
      Interview. Friedman was a reporter for the New York Post.
    - Friele, Berent - Interview 1, 1982 September 29; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9545A)
      Interview. Friele was senior vice presdient and director of AIA and an adviser on international relations for Nelson Rockefeller when he was governor of New York and Vice President of the United States.
    - Friele, Berent - Interview 2, 1982 October 7; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9545B)
    - Galvin, Edward, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9546)
      Interview. Galvin was a bodyguard for Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Gardner, John, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9547)
      Interview. Gardner was a trustee for the Rockefeller Brothers Fund.
    - Gart, Murray, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9548)
      Interview. Gart was a journalist and Rockefeller campaign aide. Gart interview starts at 10 minutes, 30 seconds and ends at 78 minutes, 18 seconds. Tape is then blank until 90 minutes, 19 seconds, when there is a partial interview with Bernard Newman until end of tape. Newman was a Republican leader who was appointed to the New York State Supreme Court by Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Germond, Jack, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9549)
      Interview. Germond was a journalist.
    - Gettinger, Jason, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9550)
      Interview. Gettinger was an attorney.
    - Gilder, George, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9551)
      Interview. Gilder was a speechwriter for Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Gillies, John, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9552)
      Interview. Gillies was an IBEC and gubernatorial aide.
    - Gilpatric, Roswell, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9553)
      Interview. Roswell was a Rockefeller Brothers' Special Studies panelist. Roswell interview ends at 39 minutes, 53 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Robert Bennett until end. Bennett was superintendent of the Executive Mansion.
    - Goldberg, David, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9554)
      Interview. Goldberg was a political consultant.
    - Goldman, Pat, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9555)
      Interview. Goldman was chair of the Republican Women's Task Force.
    - Goldstone, Harmon, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9556)
      Interview. Goldstone was an accomplished architect who knew Nelson Rockefeller dating back to their years at the Lincoln School in Manhattan.
    - Golub, William, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9557)
      Interview. Golub was an attorney who was Special Assistant to Governor Nelson Rockefeller for rail and commuter problems. He was also a special consultant to the Moreland Act Commission to draft legislation that created sweeping changes in New York State's liquor laws.
    - Gotbaum, Victor, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9558)
      Interview. Gotbaum was a New York City labor leader and executive director of the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) District Council 37.
    - Gould, Sam, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9559)
      Interview. Gould was chancellor of the State University of New York.
    - Graves, Guy, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9560)
      Interview. Graves was a New York state Republican committee leader from Schenectady in the 1960s. Graves interview ends at 125 minutes, 40 seconds. Tape then contains parital interview with Perry Duryea until end. Duryea was a Republican leader of the New York State Assembly.
    - Gregg, Hugh and Kay, and Teague, Bert, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9561)
      Interview. Hugh Gregg was leader of Governor Nelson Rockefeller's 1964 Presidential campaign in New Hampshire. Teague was Gregg's protg and campaign aide.
    - Grimm, Robert, and Russo, Louis, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9562)
      Interview. Grimm was Erie County Republican Chairman. Russo was budget director for Erie County.
    - Grindle, Paul, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9563)
      Interview. Grindle was a businessman and leader of Henry Cabot Lodge Jr.'s 1964 Presidential campaign.
    - Gwirtzman, Milton, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9769)
      Interview. Gwirtzman was an advisor and speech writer for John, Robert, and Edward Kennedy. This is the end of the interview contained on AV 9770.
    - Gyory, Bruce, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9564)
      Interview. Gyory was a political consultant.
  - H-K, 2.4
    - Hall, Robert, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9565)
      Interview. Hall was a newspaper editor and publisher who was appointed by Governor Nelson Rockefeller to serve on the Temporary Study Commission on the Future of the Adirondacks.
    - Halberg, Herbert B., circa1980s; Sound, 85 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9674)
      Interview. Halberg was Special New York City field coordinator for Governor Nelson Rockefeller's 1970 reelection bid, and former Commissioner of Marine and Aviation in Mayor John Lindsay's administration. Halberg interview ends at 47 minutes, 1 second. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual until 70 minutes, 32 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with George Dudley until end. Dudley was an architect and gubernatorial aide.
    - Harding, Raymond, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9566)
      Interview. Harding was Bronx County Liberal Party chairman and then state Liberal Party chairman. Harding interview ends at 47 minutes, 4 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Paul Volcker until end. Volcker was an economist for the Federal Reserve Bank of New York (1952-1957) and then Chase Manhattan Bank (1957-1962). He was also chairman of the Federal Reserve, 1979-1987.
    - Harrison, Ellen, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9567)
      Interview. Harrison was the wife of Wallace K. Harrison, who was an architect and friend and advisor to Nelson Rockefeller. She was also the sister of David Milton, who was husband of Abby (Babs) Rockefeller, who was Nelson Rockefeller's sister. Harrison interview ends at 106 minutes, 5 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Louis Lefkowitz until end. Lefkowitz was New York Attorney General, 1957-1978.
    - Hart, Kitty Carlisle, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9568)
      Interview. Carlisle Hart was an actress and special advisor to Governor Nelson Rockefeller on opportunities for women.
    - Hartmann, Robert, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9569)
      Interview. Hartmann was a reporter for the Los Angeles Times, an editor and public relations consultant for the Republican Conference of the U.S. House of Representatives, and an aide to Gerald R. Ford.
    - Haskell, Hal, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9570)
      Interview. Haskell worked with Nelson Rockefeller at IBEC, served under Rockefeller in the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare during the presidency of Dwight D. Eisenhower, and he was a consultant to Rockefeller when Rockefeller served as President Eisenhower's special assistant for Foreign Affairs. Haskell interview ends at 136 minutes, 10 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Fergus Reid III until end. Reid was an investment banker and financial adviser to the Rockefeller family and was a campaign aide to John Lindsay.
    - Hausbeck, Albert, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9571)
      Interview. Hausbeck was a member of the New York State Assembly.
    - Heckscher II, August - Part 1, 1982 March 31; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9572A)
      Interview. Hecksher was a consultant for the Special Studies Project. He was also Parks Commissioner of New York City under Mayor John Lindsay.
    - Heckscher II, August - Part 2, 1982 March 31?; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9572B)
      Interview. Hecksher was a consultant for the Special Studies Project. He was also Parks Commissioner of New York City under Mayor John Lindsay. Heckscher interview ends at 56 minutes, 34 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual until end.
    - Helmuth, James, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9573)
      Interview. Helmuth was a campaign aide. Helmuth interview ends at 17 minutes, 22 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with William St. Thomas until end. St. Thomas was a Republican county leader.
    - Herter, Susan, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9574)
      Interview. Herter worked in Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs office; as an U.S. Department of State associate; on the Museum of Modern Art staff; and then was chief of staff when Nelson Rockefeller was Vice President.
    - Hevesi, Alan, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9575)
      Interview. Hevesi was a member of the New York State Assembly. Hevesi interview ends at 42 minutes, 51 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Stuart Spencer until end. Spencer managed Nelson Rockefeller's 1964 presdiential campaign.
    - Hewitt, Ben, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9576)
      Interview. Hewitt was Niagara County (NY) Republican leader.
    - Hightower, John, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9577)
      Interview. Hightower was executive director of the New York State Council on the Arts and then director of the Museum of Modern Art.
    - Hiss, Alger, 1982 April 22; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15678)
      Interview. Hiss was involved in the establishment of the United Nations both as a U.S. State Department official and as a United Nations official. At the United Nations Conference on International Organization (the convention that created the U.N. charter), Hiss and Nelson Rockefeller were members of the United States delegation, with Hiss also serving as secretary general of the conference. Hiss and some other members of the U.S. delegation opposed the admission of Argentina while Rockefeller supported the country's admission.
    - Hiss, Donald, 1982 September 15; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15680)
      Interview. Hiss was the brother of Alger Hiss and worked in the State Department during World War II. His work focused on limiting German economic interests in Latin America.
    - Hooker, Roger, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9580)
      Interview. Hooker was deputy secretary to Governor Nelson Rockefeller and administrative assistant for Congressional affairs when Rockefeller was Vice President.
    - Hopkins, Stephen, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9581)
      Interview. Hopkins was the director of the New York State Office in Washington D.C.
    - Horn, Francis, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9582)
      Interview. Horn was a Dartmouth classmate. Horn interview ends 146 minutes, 38 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Frank O'Connor and Jim O'Donnell until end. O'Connor was the Democratic nominee for governor of New York in 1966. O'Donnell was an aide to O'Connor.
    - Houseman, Sam - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9583)
      Interview. Houseman was a businessman and prominent Republican fundraiser. Houseman interview ends at 26 minutes, 21 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with an unidentified female VP of General Motors until 35 minutes, 55 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual until end.
    - Houseman, Sam - Part 2, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9584)
      Interview. Houseman was a businessman and Republican fundraiser. Houseman interview ends at 29 minutes, 45 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with an unidentified individual until end.
    - Humphreys, George, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9585)
      Interview. Humphreys was deputy director of Governor Nelson Rockefeller's reelection campaign in 1970 and then appointed assistant Commissioner of Environmental Conservation for New York City Affairs.
    - Hurd, T. Norman, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9579)
      Interview. Hurd was budget director for New York State under Governor Nelson Rockefeller, and previously for Governor Thomas E. Dewey. He also served Rockefeller as Housing Finance Authority and Advisor to the Governor on Attica Prison riot.
    - Ingraham, Hollis, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9589)
      Interview. Ingraham was New York State Commissioner of Health.
    - Innes, John, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9590)
      Interview. Innes was a Republican county chairman. Innes's wife also appears on the tape. Innes interview ends at 88 minutes, 53 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Harold Fisher until 104 minutes, 18 seconds. Fisher was appointed to the board of the Metropolitan Transportation Authority by Governor Nelson Rockefeller in 1968. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual until end.
    - Ives, Martin, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9591)
      Interview. Ives was deputy controller of the State of New York.
    - Jerry, Harold, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9592)
      Interview. Jerry was a New York State senator, 1959-1962, and, under Governor Nelson Rockefeller, Jerry was the director of the Office for Regional Development and then the first director of the Office of Planning Coordination.
    - Jackson, John - Part 1, 1982 November 29; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15673)
      Interview. Jackson was vice president, producer, and director of stage operations at Radio City Music Hall.
    - Jackson, John - Part 2, 1982 November 29; Sound, 7 minutes (Tape AV 15683)
    - Johnson, John, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15674)
      Interview. Johnson served on the Dormitory Authority of the State of New York under Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Johnson, Philip, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9593)
      Interview. Johnson was a noted architect whose association with Nelson Rockefeller began in the early 1930s, when they both served on the Junior Advisory Committee of the Museum of Modern Artm and continued throughout the Governor's lifetime. Among other things, he designed the Rockefeller Guest House for the family. Johnson interview ends at 31 minutes, 14 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with John Debbink until end. Debbink was a long-time employee at General Motors who headed the Delco Moraine division.
    - Kaplan, Betsy, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15672)
      Interview. Kaplan was St. Lawrence County (NY) Republican chair from 1970 to 1976.
    - Keene, Robert, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9594)
      Interview. Keene was a Dartmouth classmate of Nelson Rockefeller. Interview with Keene starts at 9 minutes, 26 seconds and ends at 45 minutes, 33 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with an individual identiifed as a manager of a research department at a brokerage firm until end.
    - Kiepper, Jim, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9595)
      Interview. Kiepper was an advance man for Governor Nelson Rockefeller during his 1968 presidential campaign.
    - Kimball, Edward, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9596)
      Interview. Employee of Venezuela Basic Ecomony Corporation (VBEC), which was founded by Nelson Rockefeller. Specifically, he managed INLACA, which was VBEC's successful milk pasteurization company.
    - Kingston,John, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9597)
      Interview. Kingston was New York State Assembly Majority Leader
    - Kintner, William, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9598)
      Interview. Kintner was a member of the National Security Council planning board and assisted Nelson Rockefeller on the Planning Coordination Group's study on the assessment of Soviet vulnerabilities. Kintner interview ends at 91 minutes, 45 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Edward Kimball until end. Kimball was and IBEC aide.
    - Kissinger, Henry, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9599)
      Interview. Kissinger was a longtime advisor to Nelson Rockefeller: Director of his Special Studies Project for the Rockefeller Brothers Fund in the late 1950s, foreign policy advisor to Nelson Rockefeller's presidential campaigns, and later as U.S. Secretary of State in the Nixon and Ford Administrations. Kissinger interview ends at 111 minutes, 17 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Charles Lanigan until end. Lanigan was New York State Republican chair.
    - Koch, Edward, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9600)